<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ibmi on Barrett Otte</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.io/tags/ibmi/</link><description>Recent content in ibmi on Barrett Otte</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://barrettotte.github.io/tags/ibmi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jupyter Notebooks + IBM i</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2020/5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2020/5/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
This is going to be a short post on calling basic IBMi DB2 statements from Jupyter Notebooks. It is really light on explanation, so I encourage googling terms you are not familiar with.
Briefest Introduction to Jupyter Jupyter provides an environment for executing live code in a notebook like format. I find these especially useful for keeping &amp;ldquo;living notes&amp;rdquo; for mathematics and production support notes.
A notebook consists of cells, which allow you to mix and match SQL, Markdown, Python, Javascript, and much more in the same notebook.</description></item><item><title>Sending a Text Message with Twilio and DB2 SQL</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2020/3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2020/3/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
This is going to be a pretty short post, but I thought it would be fun to share this in light of the Twilio + DEV hackathon this month. Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if either project I planned out will be finished in time. This month went by way too fast, so the outlook is not good.
Since I&amp;rsquo;m still a pretty new IBMi developer, I found that the best way to learn this new world was to take a fun idea and see if it was possible to do with RPG and/or DB2 SQL.</description></item><item><title>Writing an IBM i Syntax Highlighter for VS Code</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2020/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2020/2/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
Introduction I love VS Code and really want it to be the &amp;ldquo;all in one&amp;rdquo; editor. Unfortunately, there are still plenty of fringe cases that just don&amp;rsquo;t work yet.
To make a long stort short, I recently started working as an IBMi developer. Its a midrange system (the middle ground between standard server and mainframe) that uses an old programming language called RPG (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IBM_RPG, the same era as COBOL and FORTRAN).</description></item><item><title>IBM i Joke Program</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2020/1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2020/1/</guid><description>My coworker found a really cool command called STRPCCMD that allows the 5250 emulator to execute commands on the client machine. So why not exploit it for a laugh&amp;hellip;
joke.clle
/* CALL BOLIB/JOKE */ /* Entry Path: C:\Users\Public\IBM\ClientSolutions */ PGM DCL VAR(&amp;amp;gist) TYPE(*CHAR) LEN(60) DCL VAR(&amp;amp;cmd) TYPE(*CHAR) LEN(120) CHGVAR VAR(&amp;amp;gist) VALUE('https://gist.github.com/' + || 'b6654e5606831f13f48887de39d67723.git') CHGVAR VAR(&amp;amp;cmd) VALUE('cmd /c &amp;quot;git clone ' || &amp;amp;gist || ' x' + || ' &amp;amp; powershell x/joke.</description></item><item><title>IBM i Book Chapters 1 and 2</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2019/5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2019/5/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
This is a post to say that I have &amp;ldquo;completed&amp;rdquo; the first two chapters of my small &amp;ldquo;book&amp;rdquo; Learning IBM i as a Lowly Web Developer. (Most of the core content is in an acceptable state, but may still be tweaked when I read it over for the millionth time).
The work in progress can be found at https://barrettotte.github.io/IBMi-Book/#/
Preface It should be obvious, but I&amp;rsquo;m not a writer and barely a programmer sometimes.</description></item><item><title>Utility to Pull Code from IBM i</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2019/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2019/2/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
In one of my really dumb side projects I&amp;rsquo;m making, I have some IBM i code that I&amp;rsquo;d like to keep in my git repository with some other stuff. I could use the Integrated File System (IFS), but truthfully I don&amp;rsquo;t know enough about IBM i yet to use it correctly.
So, in the meantime I have a quick and dirty python script that lets me pull multiple source members based on a config file, repo.</description></item><item><title>RPG and IBM i</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2019/1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.io/posts/2019/1/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
This is my first post to DEV to see if there are any developers on here who have messed around with IBM i before or are interested in learning what it is. Primarily, I will be focusing on the history of IBM i and the RPG programming language that has evolved with it.
At my current workplace, I noticed this ominous green and black screen on numerous older developers' monitors.</description></item></channel></rss>