<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rpgle on Barrett Otte</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/tags/rpgle/</link><description>Recent content in rpgle on Barrett Otte</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://barrettotte.github.com/tags/rpgle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Writing an IBM i Syntax Highlighter for VS Code</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/10/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
Introduction I love VS Code and really want it to be the &amp;ldquo;all in one&amp;rdquo; editor. Unfortunately, there are still plenty of fringe cases that just don&amp;rsquo;t work yet.
To make a long stort short, I recently started working as an IBMi developer. Its a midrange system (the middle ground between standard server and mainframe) that uses an old programming language called RPG (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IBM_RPG, the same era as COBOL and FORTRAN).</description></item><item><title>IBM i Book Chapters 1 and 2</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/8/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
This is a post to say that I have &amp;ldquo;completed&amp;rdquo; the first two chapters of my small &amp;ldquo;book&amp;rdquo; Learning IBM i as a Lowly Web Developer. (Most of the core content is in an acceptable state, but may still be tweaked when I read it over for the millionth time).
The work in progress can be found at https://barrettotte.github.io/IBMi-Book/#/
Preface It should be obvious, but I&amp;rsquo;m not a writer and barely a programmer sometimes.</description></item><item><title>Utility to Pull Code from IBM i</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/5/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
In one of my really dumb side projects I&amp;rsquo;m making, I have some IBM i code that I&amp;rsquo;d like to keep in my git repository with some other stuff. I could use the Integrated File System (IFS), but truthfully I don&amp;rsquo;t know enough about IBM i yet to use it correctly.
So, in the meantime I have a quick and dirty python script that lets me pull multiple source members based on a config file, repo.</description></item><item><title>RPG and IBM i</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/4/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
This is my first post to DEV to see if there are any developers on here who have messed around with IBM i before or are interested in learning what it is. Primarily, I will be focusing on the history of IBM i and the RPG programming language that has evolved with it.
At my current workplace, I noticed this ominous green and black screen on numerous older developers' monitors.</description></item></channel></rss>