<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>python on Barrett Otte</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in python on Barrett Otte</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://barrettotte.github.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Useless Information: QR Codes</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/17/</guid><description>I randomly decided to learn about how QR codes work. It turns out there&amp;rsquo;s some pretty cool things to learn such as Reed-Solomon Error Correction and Galois Fields.
At my job I decided to give a &amp;ldquo;Lunch and Learn&amp;rdquo; about the basics of generating a QR code in Python. The QR code generated below is a link to my GitHub profile.
This presentation was done in a Jupyter notebook interactively and has not been converted to markdown at this time.</description></item><item><title>Projectile Motion and Introduction to Octo</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/14/</guid><description>Introduction to Octo Octo is a high level assembler for an old virtual machine, CHIP-8, which was developed in the mid-1970s. Its a VM with some basic audio, graphics, and input. Game jams with constraints like this are the most fun.
I used the following resources to learn from:
Octo IDE Octo Assembly Language Manual A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Programming with Chip8 An Intermediate Guide to Game Development with Chip8 Chip8 Programming Techniques Octojam 7 I intended on attending a game jam called Octojam 7 running from 10-01-2020 to 11-01-2020.</description></item><item><title>Jupyter Notebooks + IBM i</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/13/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
This is going to be a short post on calling basic IBMi DB2 statements from Jupyter Notebooks. It is really light on explanation, so I encourage googling terms you are not familiar with.
Briefest Introduction to Jupyter Jupyter provides an environment for executing live code in a notebook like format. I find these especially useful for keeping &amp;ldquo;living notes&amp;rdquo; for mathematics and production support notes.
A notebook consists of cells, which allow you to mix and match SQL, Markdown, Python, Javascript, and much more in the same notebook.</description></item><item><title>Game of Life in TSQL</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/7/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
GIF can be seen here https://github.com/barrettotte/SQL-Game-of-Life/blob/master/demo.gif
One morning during my commute I was zoning out and realized I wanted to make a really dumb side project in SQL. One of my favorite things to do is use a language unconventionally and I thought implementing Game of Life was the perfect little project to do.
Game of Life If you are unfamiliar with Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life, I encourage to read more about it here https://en.</description></item><item><title>Utility to Pull Code from IBM i</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/5/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
In one of my really dumb side projects I&amp;rsquo;m making, I have some IBM i code that I&amp;rsquo;d like to keep in my git repository with some other stuff. I could use the Integrated File System (IFS), but truthfully I don&amp;rsquo;t know enough about IBM i yet to use it correctly.
So, in the meantime I have a quick and dirty python script that lets me pull multiple source members based on a config file, repo.</description></item></channel></rss>