<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sql on Barrett Otte</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/tags/sql/</link><description>Recent content in sql on Barrett Otte</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://barrettotte.github.com/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jupyter Notebooks + IBM i</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/13/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
This is going to be a short post on calling basic IBMi DB2 statements from Jupyter Notebooks. It is really light on explanation, so I encourage googling terms you are not familiar with.
Briefest Introduction to Jupyter Jupyter provides an environment for executing live code in a notebook like format. I find these especially useful for keeping &amp;ldquo;living notes&amp;rdquo; for mathematics and production support notes.
A notebook consists of cells, which allow you to mix and match SQL, Markdown, Python, Javascript, and much more in the same notebook.</description></item><item><title>Sending a Text Message with Twilio and DB2 SQL</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/11/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
This is going to be a pretty short post, but I thought it would be fun to share this in light of the Twilio + DEV hackathon this month. Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if either project I planned out will be finished in time. This month went by way too fast, so the outlook is not good.
Since I&amp;rsquo;m still a pretty new IBMi developer, I found that the best way to learn this new world was to take a fun idea and see if it was possible to do with RPG and/or DB2 SQL.</description></item><item><title>Game of Life in TSQL</title><link>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://barrettotte.github.com/posts/7/</guid><description>Migrated post from DEV.to
GIF can be seen here https://github.com/barrettotte/SQL-Game-of-Life/blob/master/demo.gif
One morning during my commute I was zoning out and realized I wanted to make a really dumb side project in SQL. One of my favorite things to do is use a language unconventionally and I thought implementing Game of Life was the perfect little project to do.
Game of Life If you are unfamiliar with Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life, I encourage to read more about it here https://en.</description></item></channel></rss>